Super Top Up Insurance.  What is Super Top Up
Insurance?  Super top up is
insurance that gives you additional cover
at a very low price.  Meaning,
in ₹1000-₹2000 a year, you get insurance up to ₹90 lakh.
So an additional
layer is being formed.  You are getting a buffer
on your base health insurance policy
which can protect you in case of a big claim.
How Super Topup works.  Let us understand it once in simple language.
Super Topup has a
deductible.  Meaning there is an amount
of ₹5 lakh deductible from the let and there
is insurance of ₹25 lakh.  So if your
hospital bill crosses ₹5 lakh then this
₹25 lakh will be activated.  So to cross this ₹ 5 lakh,
you can either take this ₹ 5 lakh
from your base policy.  5 lakh if ​​you
have corporate cover.  You can take it from there.
You can also pay Rs 5 lakh yourself.
Many times you people ask the question that if
I do not have a base policy then can I
buy super topup directly or
not?  You can definitely buy it.  But
you have to pay the initial deductible amount once a year, it is the annual aggregate deductible.  After that your super topup gets
activated.  So what is the benefit of Super Topup
?  Firstly,
you get the policy at a low premium.
More cover at a lower cost.  There is inflation protection so that
if you have a policy of Rs 5 lakh now and
you do not want to increase the base amount due to ex-
gratia reasons or you feel that the
premium will become high and you do not want to increase it, then
you can give yourself inflation protection by taking a super top-up so that
if the
treatment cost increases tomorrow, my super top-
up policy will protect me.
Who should take it?  According to me, everyone should take a
super top-up policy.  Even if you have
taken a good base policy, you
can still take a super top up.  Because
you get super top up insurance at a very low cost.
If you are holding corporate insurance
and you feel that
you do not want to buy your base policy separately, then you can take a super top-up
policy with a deductible amount.
Infact based policies also come with some higher
deductibles, you can also look at them.  But
super top up is cost effective.
You can take super top up along with deductible.  And
over the years you can reduce the deductible amount.
And if you are a senior citizen and
you feel that your base
premium will increase significantly if you enhance your base
cover, then you
can enhance your coverage by taking a super top up
at a lower premium.  So make sure that
it has to come in a combination.  Otherwise,
you will have to pay the initial deductible amount.
Many people also do this by
taking a small deductible amount.  Suppose a
deduction of ₹1 lakh is taken.
Took super top up on top of that.  What will happen with that?  If there
is a base policy, then the cost will be controlled
because Rs 1 lakh is deductible and if
any claim comes then you will have to pay Rs 1 lakh.
So in today's video we will talk about
which five super top up plans
you can consider,
we will share their comparison with you, what are the
similarities, what are the differences,
what are their prices, who can buy them and so on, so we will
talk in full detail
about these five plans so that you too
can buy a good super top up policy for your family
[Music]
Quick reminder before starting the video,
if you have not yet subscribed to our channel, do it
so that you get the right
information at the right time, let's move
towards the video, so here the plans we are comparing are
Neevapa Health Recharge, HDFC Argo
Medya Super Top Up IC, LBR Activate Booster,
Aitya B, Birla Super Top Up Plan B and
Tata AIG's Medi Plus, these are the five plans we are
comparing.  Please
check the incurred claim ratio of the companies before comparing.
Incident Claim Ratio is the
Amount Settlement Ratio, which means how much amount
came to the insurance company and how much
they settled, which means if ₹100 came and
they paid ₹80 in the claim form, then
80% is the Incident Claim Ratio, so ICAR
Niba's is 61.22, this is as per IDS
letter latest report, HDFC Ago's is
84.85, ICICI's is 82.24, Aitya Birla's
is 71.5, Tata AIG's is 76.24. Now we will talk about
room eligibility, which rooms are
available?  What
room categories can you avail under your policy?
Single Private AC Room at Neema Health Recharge
, No Room Rent Capping at HDFC Ago.
ICIC Lambar offers single private
AC room.  No room rent capping in Aditya Birla,
no room rent capping in Tata AI also.
Minimum and maximum entry age.  So the
minimum entry age in NIVAPA is
18 years.  The maximum is 65 years.
Dependent children can stay in the family for a period ranging from 91 days to 30
years.
People between 18 to 65 years of age can take the policy in HDFC Arbo Medi Share Super Topup.
The policy can be continued for life time.
If you take the policy today, it is
not that if you are 65 then you
cannot continue it.  You can continue this for life.
If you are paying premium then you can
continue it for life time.  The age of the child
is 91 days to 23 years.
18 Years to 125 Years in ICSC Lomard Activate Booster.
Meaning it is a whole life policy.  Anyone can
take it at any age.  91 days to
30 years is the child's dependent age.
In Aditya Birla Super Top Up, you can
take the policy between 18 years to 65 years.
Dependent age is 91 days to 25 years.
Tata IG Medic Plus: 18 to 65
dependents 91 to 91 days to 25 years.
Minimum and maximum sum assured.  The minimum sum assured
in Asserva Health recharge is ₹5 lakh.
The maximum is Rs 95 lakh.
Minimum sum assured available in Mesur Super Topup in HDFC Ago
is Rs 3 lakh and maximum is Rs 20 lakh.
Sum assured ranging from Rs 10 lakh to Rs 4.9 crore
is available in ICIC Lambar.  Cover ranging
from Rs 10 lakh to Rs 95 lakh
is available at Aitya Birla in Activate Ber.  Cover ranging from Rs 5 lakh to Rs
1 crore is available in Tata EIG.
Deductible is an option available which we
talked about that the initial amount will
not be charged on the policy.  That initial amount will have to be set at the
time of taking the policy.
Accordingly the premium is decided.
Meaning higher deductible lower premium.  Now
understand the concept.  As soon as the deductible is getting
higher, the company knows that
if you are taking my deductible of Rs 5 lakh, then the
company knows that I will not have to pay the first 5 lakh
from this policy, so the premium is being
decided accordingly.  If you
take a Rs 10 lakh deductible, the premium will be further reduced.
Because the company knows that my
liability is to pay Rs 10 lakh, otherwise the
premium will be reduced further.  If you have a
provision to pay the initial amount.
You have a base policy, a policy with good cover,
then go for a higher deductible.
What deductible options are available?  Neevapar has
deductible options ranging from Rs 1 lakh to Rs 10 lakh.
HDFC Ago has deductible options ranging from Rs 2 lakh to Rs 5 lakh.
ICICI Activate
Booster has deductible options ranging from Rs 3 lakh to Rs 20 lakh.
Aitya Birla has a
deductible of Rs 5 lakh to Rs 15 lakh.  Tata
AIG also has deductible options of 2, 3, 5, 10, 15 and 20 lakh.
Meaning if your base
policy runs for 20 then go for deductible
of 20.  In ICIC and Tata AIG we have
this option policy tenure One
year, two year, three year policy tenure
is available in Neeva BPA One year, two year, three year policy tenure is available in HDFC Ago
One
year, two year, three year option is available
In Aditya Birla Super Topper you can take one year, two year,
three year policy and
you can also take Tata IG Medical Plus for one year, two year, three
year bonus means additional bonus
what will you get Cumulative bonus If you are
running the policy then will the company
give you bonus every year Loyalty addition is available in Neeva BPA
which goes up to a maximum of 50%
and this is only in policies up to Rs. 25 lakh.  It's
not up to him.  Other companies do
not give you any bonus.  Now understand
because this policy is super top up.  If it is at a lower
cost then you will get fewer features.
Day Care Procedures
Day care procedures are covered up
to sum assured in all policies.  Aitya is listed in Birla and
Tata in AIG.  Aitya Birla has
586 procedures listed and Tata AIG has 540
plus procedures listed.  There
is no list of other companies.  All day care
procedures are covered.  Home care treatment.
Not covered under NIVAPA.
Covered up to sum assured in HDFCO.  ICICI LBAD will
cover 5% of Annual Sum Assured.
Home care treatment will be covered up to a maximum of Rs 5 lakh.
Covered up to Rs 5,000 in Aditya Birla
and also covered up to sum assured in Tata Agio.
So in home care, there are some
treatments like chemotherapy,
dialysis which you can get done at home also.  So
that is also covered in these policies.  Domiciliary
Hospitalization.  Domiciliary hospitalization is
where you have to be
hospitalized at home because
beds are not available in the hospital.  So
in Neevapa Health Recharge now covered up to
sum assured.  HDFC is not covered under Arco.
Covered up to sum assured in ICS Alamba.
Also covered in Aditya Birla
and also covered in Tata AG Medical Plus.
AYUSH hospitalization which is Ayurveda,
Yoga, Unani Siddha, Homeopathy, these also have
hospitalization.  So that is also covered
in your policies,
up to sum assured is covered in Niva Health Recharge.
HDFC if not covered in ago.
Covered up to sum assured in ICICI LBAD, covered up to sum assured
in Aditya Birla and also covered up to sum assured in Tata Ag.
Organ Donor Transplant:
If organ donation is taking place and the bill
amount is high, then that is also covered.
Harvesting costs are covered.  All
companies are covered up to the sum assured.   Let's
talk about refill benefits.  Refills are
available in your base policies.
But anything will be available in Super Topper policies.
Maximum policies will not provide refill
benefit.  It gets refilled.  If your base sum
assured gets exhausted, it will be refilled again.
But here, since the sum assured
is high and the cost is low, refill
benefit is not available.  Neema
is not available in BPA.  HDFC Ago also does not have it.
Not even in ICICI.
Not even in Aditya Birla.  Only Tata Yaji has it.
Restore is available for unrelated illnesses.   If
needed for any other disease,
you can take Restore.  Emergency Road
Ambulance.  Neema Boo Health Recharge has
hospitalization at Rs 1500.  Not covered in HDFC Ergo.
Coverage up to sum assured in ICICI.
If Aditya Birla
is a network provider then there are actual expenses.
If you go to a non-network hospital, the
hospitalization there is Rs 5000.
Tata will provide hospitalization at IG for Rs 3000.
Emergency air ambulances are
not covered under the domestic air ambulance scheme.
Not covered even in HDFCO.  ICIC Low is a
rider in LBAD.  Add-on is available to
add domestic air ambulance.  Similarly, you can
also add your Aditya Birla through rider.
Tata is also not available in IG.
Annual health checkup.  So
complimentary annual health checkup is
included in your policies.
You can get a preventive health checkup done once a year.
Neevapa is not available in HDFC Ergo.
Plan A is
not available in ICSC.  Available in Plan B.
You can add it with the rider.  And it
is cashless.  The maximum limit is ₹5,000.
This is not available in Aditya Birla.
Preventive health checkup.  Tata Ag
offers 1% off base sum up to a maximum of
₹10,000.  You get this for every block of two claim free
years.  If
you do not make a claim continuously for two years, then you
can avail this preventive health checkup of Rs 10,000.  Now let us come to pre and post
hospitalization expenses.  This means that
you can get reimbursed the pre-hospital expenses as well as the post-hospital expenses.
In Neevapa Health Recharge, 60 days before, 90 days after,
in HDFC Ago, 30 days before, 60 days after,
in ICICI Lo LBA, 90 days before, 180
days after, two plans are available in Plan A and 60 and 90 in Plan
B.  You have
30 and 60 days in Aditya Birla.  You can pre-pay your
60 and 90 days
pre and post hospitalization expenses with Tata AIG Medic Plus.
E-consultation and
unlimited tele-consultation are available in health recharge.
You can avail this from Neevapa Health App.  Not available in HDFCO
[sound of clearing throat].
You
can add a rider to ICICI LBARAD, which is unlimited tele-
consultation which you can avail through the IL Tech Care app.  It
is not available even in Aditya Birla and is available in your Tata LG
and second medical opinion is also available for specific
illnesses.  Modern treatments and
robotic surgeries.  So you know that nowadays
hospitals have started your advanced treatment.
Robotic assisted surgeries have been started.
So that is also covered in these policies.
Neeva Health is covered in recharge.
Accept there is 1 lakh submit on few
robotic surgeries.  HDFC Ergo also has cover
up to sum assured.  In ICICI, Aditya
Birla, Tata all are covered up to sum
assured.  Non-payable items are consumable
items that are not covered under your super top-up
policies.  As I
told you, Super Topup is a cheap way to
get a good high cover.  So it
is not available in HDFC Niva.
You can add rider in ICICI.  You
can add a claim protector rider to cover non-
payable items.  Rest is not covered in Aditya Birla.
And Tata IG has it inbuilt.
Tata IG also has your consumable
items inbuilt.  Copayment.  So there
is no copayment in Niva BPUPA.  There
is a clause in HDFC Algo that if you are above 80 years of age then
10% co-payment
is mandatory for you.  Rest there is no copayment in ICICI, Aditya Birla
or Tata.
Premium 8 slab: The 8 slab of premium is for five
years each.
Your premiums increase every five-year slab in all these
companies.  The rest may
increase in between due to inflation.  But Ath
Slab is five years.  Let's talk about waiting periods.  The
initial waiting period
is 30 days.  Plant hospitalization claim cannot be made for the first 30 days in all policies.
Slow growing illnesses, which are
called specific exclusions, are
not covered for 24 months.  You have the
option in ICICI to reduce it
with the help of a rider.
You can reduce it by paying add-on premium.
Then there are pre-existing diseases.
Its waiting period is 36 months in all the
policies.  And the ICC Low NMAD Activate Booster has the
option to reduce it with additional riders.
Now let's talk about
which optional riders are available.
Neevapa Health Recharge offers PA cover
which includes Accidental Death, Accidental
Permanent Total Disability, Accidental
Permanent Partial Disability
cover ranging from Rs 1 lakh to Rs 50 lakh.  Meaning there
is an option to add.  CI List of 20 Illnesses.  If
you want to cover critical illness, there
is an add-on for that too.  There is a list of 20 illnesses
which you will get and sum assured ranging
from Rs 1 lakh to Rs 10
lakh is available with a survival period of 30 days.  There are no riders available
with HDFC Ergo MD Share Super Topup.
ICICI has a lot of
riders.  Meaning, you should understand
that it is as good as a base policy.  So
if you are looking for a good super top-up policy then
ICICI is a comprehensive policy.
But again, don't forget to do your due diligence.
This is to the information that we are sharing
to the best of our knowledge.  According to our research,
but take a decision only after doing your due diligence.
This is not a policy advice that
you should take this policy.  Do your due
diligence and take your own wise decisions.
ICC Labrador has a Jump Start Rider in
which you can learn ABCD first in
30 days.  ABCDE is that you can bring asthma,
BP, cholesterol, diabetes on day one.
B fifit hai which is
an OPD rider.  You can get domestic air ambulance
cover.  Claim Protector
for Non-Payable Items Coverage.  Inflation
protector is also available so that your
sum assured keeps increasing every year according to inflation.  There
is a dependent accommodation benefit.
Preventive health checkup.  Guaranteed
reduction of deductible.  If you choose this rider, the
deductible is reduced by 10% every year.
Up to 50% will have to be
taken at Inception only.  E-Consultation, Unlimited
Telecons, Nursing at Home, Compassionate.  There are a lot of
riders that you can see.
Room modifier rider is also available.  Where
you can convert a single room into an any room
or take a single room on twin
sharing basis.
Network Advantage where you get 10%
discount and 20%.  You are
reducing your cashless network.
Suppose there is a network of 12,000 hospitals.
You say reduce me.
Give me network advantage.
You take that 12,000 to 8,000 and you are okay with that.
So you get 10% discount
on premium.  But if any claim comes
outside the network, Network Advantage which
is a tiered network, then there is also a 20% co-payment.   There are
no add-ons available at Aditya Birla.  Add-ons like Global Cover and
Accidental Death Benefit are available in Tata IG.
So now let's talk about premiums.
How much will this premium actually cost?
How many covers?  Here, for comparison, I have
taken Rs 5 lakh deductible in all the policies.
So that will be an Apple to Apple comparison.
I have attained the age of 35 years.
What is the premium if someone is taking a policy with a 5% deductible
?  I have taken 95 lakh coverage of NIV bua
with 5 lakh deductible, the
premium is 25. Okay, now we will talk
about HDFCO because the maximum cover
available is 20 lakhs, so 20 lakh cover with 5
lakh deductible, the premium is 2200. If we
talk about ICICI LBAD,
I have not taken any rider yet, you can take that as per
your convenience. 95 lakh cover with 5 lakh
deductible is costing 4137
Aditya Birla's 95 with 5 lakh deductible is
4303 Tigg's is 4827 1 crore 5 lakh
deductible was the same option.  Now here I will
also show you with 10 lakh deductible.
What will happen with that?  You will find that a
higher deductible means lower costs.  Now if
I take 90 to 10 lakh deductible for Niva, then the
premium will be 865, which will become 1/3rd of the premium by
taking higher deductible.  So this means
that instead of
taking the combination of 5 lakh plus 95, take at least the combination of 90 with 10.
To make your policy cost effective
and easy to manage as well.  Because
if you get more claims than the base covers then it is better
because some things as you saw are
not covered in the super top up.  There is no option of Rs 10 lakh deductible in HDFC Ago,
so I did
not share it.  In ICICI you will see that the
cost is Rs 90 lakh with Rs 10 lakh deductible, which is Rs 1695,
reducing the cost by more than half.  Here
in Aditya Birla 90 lakh with 10 lakh deductible
costing 2414 and 1 crore with 10 lakh
deductible for Tata AIGS costing 3491.
So these were the details about Super Topper Plan.
We talked about what are Super Topper Plans
?  How can you use it?  Who
should you buy and we
also compared five super top-up policies with the
differences, similarities and
pricing.  So now you are assuredly ready to make an
informed decision on which Super
Topup is best for your family.  I
would like to give one more tip here.  It is better to
take the base policy and super top-up policy from the same company.  So that claim
handling becomes a little easier.  Meaning,
with the hospital also, management becomes easy for one company.  If
two policies are being used for one cashless
hospitalization, then
generally a claim settlement letter is asked for
from the second policy.  So if both are the same
companies then it will be easier to manage.
So it is better to take from the same company only.  So this was all about
Super Top Up that I
wanted to share with you.  If you
found the video useful, please
share it with your friends and family and don't
forget to subscribe to our channel.  So that
you keep getting the right information at the right time
and we will try our best to
bring good videos for you.   We
bring good information for you and
our series of videos should continue like this.
If you want to connect with our team, please do so.  The
phone number
is mentioned below.  There is also a Google form, please fill it out.
Our team will connect you.
You can write us an email at info@hp.com.   You
can WhatsApp
on 965070699.  See you in the next video.  Till then
stay safe.  Take care.  Bye-bye.   Om Om